Welcome to TP Insights. Today we are going to
talk about ICP.
What is ICP? What are the queries related to ICP? The
queries for ICP are
cashless and
reimbursement. What is the full form of ICP?
What documents do we have to
send to the insurance company for ICP?
We are going to discuss all these things in this video.
I am going to explain in detail
how we can answer this query
and what papers will be required with it. So
let's start the video
[Music]. There is
an ICP query under cashless claim and reimbursement claim.
What is ICP? Indoor case paper. Whenever
we get admitted to a hospital for treatment, the
hospital team, the nursing team
or the doctors, they
create a file related to the treatment.
It contains the entire treatment record.
Inside that file is the complete record related to the treatment.
Prescriptions are attached.
Lab test reports are entered. The
diagnosis is
written inside it. Everything from the beginning till the end.  They provide
treatment till the end, from
all the medicines to all the reports, they
enter everything in that file, the
same is called ICP by the insurance company. The
query for ICP is
raised in cashless claims
but is more in reimbursement claims.
What happens in that is that the insurance
company asks for ICP, asks for indoor case papers,
asks for cashless claims, so there is
a TPA team inside the hospital, they
scan and provide those documents to them. In that, the
entire
file has to be scanned and sent. The
treatment they are giving, the medicines
they have given or the
reports related to the treatment, after scanning everything, the
TPA team provides it to the insurance company,
that is their job. If
you get an email or message, you
can also meet the TPA team and
tell them that the insurance company has
asked for ICP related to our treatment,
indoor case papers, please
provide them. Then the TPA team
forwards the documents to
you.  Cashless approval
is received but what happens inside the reimbursement is
that many people are
not aware about it. When they are
resources, after sending the bills and reports along with the reimbursement claim form, the
insurance company asks for ICP in most of the cases,
about which people are
not aware. To help those people and to
make them aware,
I have made this video, so share this video
with as many people as possible.
What will happen from this is that those people will
get the benefit and they will
not face any problem in getting the reimbursement claim passed. What happens in it is that
when we send the
final bill, hospital's DI, summary, medicine
cable, lab test cable, lab report along with the reimbursement form,
after sending everything, the insurance company
then asks for ICP because many
times what happens is that the company is
not satisfied with those documents, they do not understand the case,
so they
ask for ICP of the hospital for confirmation related to it, they
ask for indoor case papers, so
where will we get them first of all  So
we should know what an indoor case paper is.
I have already explained
that an indoor case paper is an ICP.
When we are admitted to a hospital and
our treatment is done, a file related to that is
created. We have to send a copy of that file
to the insurance company.
Most companies use scanned copies only.
You can
make a PDF document from the scanned copy and
upload it through email or on their portal.
We will get that copy from the hospital.
Whenever an ICP is asked for indoor case papers under a rebate claim,
we have to go inside the hospital
and contact the TPA team
or their management. They will provide
you with this treatment-related file.
You will scan that file and
provide it to the insurance company,
after which your insurance claim will be
passed and you will
not face any problem. Even after that, the insurance company may
ask for some additional documents. So,
you have to check your email and messages from time to time to see
what the insurance company is asking for
and whether we have  If you are providing it,
a claim number is generated for it.
You can also track your claim by going to its website or the website of the insurance company or TPA
and can get updates
whether there is any query related to ICPA in this claim, so
you have to keep this in
mind, today I have
made a detailed video about ICPA for you, you
guys share it with your friends, if you like the
video then like it and
subscribe to the channel and if you have any
question in your mind related to ICP or health insurance, you can
write to us in the comment section or we
can write to you also, so we will meet
in the next video, till then
hello